<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-08-03T22:03:45+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/feed.xml</id><title type="html">BLUE EARTH</title><subtitle>This is a description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">On Fishing Baits</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/hobby/2023/08/02/on-fishing-baits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Fishing Baits" /><published>2023-08-02T16:38:06+02:00</published><updated>2023-08-02T16:38:06+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/hobby/2023/08/02/on-fishing-baits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/hobby/2023/08/02/on-fishing-baits.html"><![CDATA[<p>Fishing bait is any substance used to attract and catch fish, e.g. on a fishing hook. Bait items are both selected from and placed within the environment in order to capture prey. Traditionally, fishing bait is natural fish food such as night-crawlers, insects, worms, and smaller bait fish. Fishermen also use lures such as processed food, plastic baits and bionic lures to attract fish. Despite the importance of fish’s attraction to bait, the way fish react to different baits is quite poorly understood.</p>

<p>The various techniques and bait that a fisher may choose is dictated mainly by the target species and by its habitat. Bait can be separated into two main categories: artificial baits and natural baits. The alternative of artificial and live baits frequently demonstrate similar efficiency. The overall bait type and size will affect the efficiency and results of catches when fishing. With these two common ways to fish also comes environmental concerns. It is known that some bait fish are invasive and have the possibility to spread disease. A common theme when inspecting the use of artificial baits is the discarding and loss of said baits. The disposing of lures can lead to problems in the ecosystem.</p>]]></content><author><name>Michael Jenkins</name></author><category term="hobby" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fishing bait is any substance used to attract and catch fish, e.g. on a fishing hook. Bait items are both selected from and placed within the environment in order to capture prey. Traditionally, fishing bait is natural fish food such as night-crawlers, insects, worms, and smaller bait fish. Fishermen also use lures such as processed food, plastic baits and bionic lures to attract fish. Despite the importance of fish’s attraction to bait, the way fish react to different baits is quite poorly understood.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/assets/images/fishing_lures.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/assets/images/fishing_lures.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The World’s Most Popular Dog?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/pets/2023/08/01/worlds-most-popular-dog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The World’s Most Popular Dog?" /><published>2023-08-01T16:38:06+02:00</published><updated>2023-08-01T16:38:06+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/pets/2023/08/01/worlds-most-popular-dog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/pets/2023/08/01/worlds-most-popular-dog.html"><![CDATA[<p>A Bichon Frisé <em>(/ˈbiːʃɒn ˈfriːz/ or /ˈbiːʃɒn frɪˈzeɪ/; from French: bichon à poil frisé, French pronunciation: ​[biʃɔ̃ fʁize], meaning ‘curly haired dog’)</em> is a small breed of dog of the bichon type.</p>

<h1 id="etymology">Etymology</h1>

<p>The French word bichon comes from Middle French bichon (‘small dog’), a diminutive of Old French biche (‘female dog’, cognate with English bitch), from Old English bicce, and related to other Germanic words with the same meaning, including Old Norse bikkja, and German Betze. Some speculate the origin of bichon to be the result of the apheresis, or shortening, of the word barbichon (‘small poodle’), a derivative of barbiche (‘shaggy dog’); however, this is likely impossible, since the word bichon (attested 1588) is older than barbichon (attested 1694). While the English name for the breed, Bichon Frise, is derived from the French bichon à poil frisé meaning ‘curly haired small dog’.</p>]]></content><author><name>Rachel Sandrina Rissa</name></author><category term="pets" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Bichon Frisé (/ˈbiːʃɒn ˈfriːz/ or /ˈbiːʃɒn frɪˈzeɪ/; from French: bichon à poil frisé, French pronunciation: ​[biʃɔ̃ fʁize], meaning ‘curly haired dog’) is a small breed of dog of the bichon type.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/assets/images/bichon_frise.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/assets/images/bichon_frise.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The First Bees Evolved on an Ancient Supercontinent More Than 120 Million Years Ago</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/environment/2023/07/25/ancient-bees.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The First Bees Evolved on an Ancient Supercontinent More Than 120 Million Years Ago" /><published>2023-07-25T17:38:06+02:00</published><updated>2023-07-25T17:38:06+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/environment/2023/07/25/ancient-bees</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/environment/2023/07/25/ancient-bees.html"><![CDATA[<p>Working with a global team, Bossert and Almeida’s team sequenced and compared genes from more than 200 bee species. They compared them with traits from 185 different bee fossils, as well as extinct species, developing an evolutionary history and genealogical models for historical bee distribution. In what may be the broadest genomic study of bees to date, they analyzed hundreds to thousands of genes at a time to make sure that the relationships they inferred were correct.</p>

<p>“This is the first time we have broad genome-scale data for all seven bee families,” said co-author Elizabeth Murray, a WSU assistant professor of entomology.
Bees’ Evolution From Wasps</p>

<p>Previous research established that the first bees likely evolved from wasps, transitioning from predators to collectors of nectar and pollen. This study shows they arose in arid regions of western Gondwana during the early Cretaceous period.</p>

<p>“For the first time, we have statistical evidence that bees originated on Gondwana,” Bossert said. “We now know that bees are originally southern hemisphere insects.”</p>

<h2 id="ancient-amber-bee">Ancient Amber Bee</h2>

<p>A piece of ancient amber containing a tiny, fossilized bee. Bossert and colleagues from around the globe compared features of bees from fossils, including extinct species, in one of the broadest genomic studies of bees to date. Credit: Bossert lab
Geographic Expansion and Diversification of Bees</p>

<p>The researchers found evidence that as the new continents formed, bees moved north, diversifying and spreading in a parallel partnership with angiosperms, the flowering plants. Later, they colonized India and Australia. All major families of bees appeared to split off prior to the dawn of the Tertiary period, 65 million years ago—the era when dinosaurs became extinct.
Bees and Plant Biodiversity</p>

<p>The tropical regions of the western hemisphere have an exceptionally rich flora, and that diversity may be due to their longtime association with bees, authors noted. One-quarter of all flowering plants belong to the large and diverse rose family, which make up a significant share of the tropical and temperate host plants for bees.</p>]]></content><author><name>Michael Jenkins</name></author><category term="environment" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Working with a global team, Bossert and Almeida’s team sequenced and compared genes from more than 200 bee species. They compared them with traits from 185 different bee fossils, as well as extinct species, developing an evolutionary history and genealogical models for historical bee distribution. In what may be the broadest genomic study of bees to date, they analyzed hundreds to thousands of genes at a time to make sure that the relationships they inferred were correct.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/assets/images/bee.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/assets/images/bee.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Myth of the Moon Rabbit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/myth/2023/05/21/moon-rabbit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Myth of the Moon Rabbit" /><published>2023-05-21T16:38:06+02:00</published><updated>2023-05-21T16:38:06+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/myth/2023/05/21/moon-rabbit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/myth/2023/05/21/moon-rabbit.html"><![CDATA[<p>The Moon rabbit or Moon hare is a mythical figure in East Asian and indigenous American folklore, based on pareidolic interpretations that identify the dark markings on the near side of the Moon as a rabbit or hare. In East Asia, the rabbit is seen as pounding with a mortar and pestle, but the contents of the mortar differ among Chinese, Japanese, Korean and Vietnamese folklore. In Chinese folklore, the rabbit is often portrayed as a companion of the Moon goddess Chang’e, constantly pounding the elixir of life for her and some show the making of cakes or rice cakes; but in Japanese and Korean versions, the rabbit is pounding the ingredients for mochi or some other type of rice cakes; in the Vietnamese version, the Moon rabbit often appears with Hằng Nga and Chú Cuội, and like the Chinese version, the Vietnamese Moon rabbit also pounding the elixir of immortality in the mortar. In some Chinese versions, the rabbit pounds medicine for the mortals and some include making of mooncakes. Moon folklore from certain Amerindian cultures of North America also has rabbit themes and characters.</p>

<h2 id="history">History</h2>

<p>An early Chinese source called the Chu Ci, a Western Han anthology of Chinese poems from the Warring States period, notes that along with a toad, there is a hare on the Moon who constantly pounds herbs for the immortals. This notion is supported by later texts, including the Song-era Taiping Imperial Reader. As rabbits were not yet introduced to China during Western Han, the original image was not a rabbit but a hare.</p>

<p>Han Dynasty poets call the hare on the Moon the “Jade Hare” (玉兔) or the “Gold Hare” (金兔), and these phrases were used often, in place of the word for the Moon. A famous poet of Tang China, Li Bai, relates how “The rabbit in the moon pounds the medicine in vain” in his poem, “The Old Dust”.</p>]]></content><author><name>Top10 Facts</name></author><category term="myth" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Moon rabbit or Moon hare is a mythical figure in East Asian and indigenous American folklore, based on pareidolic interpretations that identify the dark markings on the near side of the Moon as a rabbit or hare. In East Asia, the rabbit is seen as pounding with a mortar and pestle, but the contents of the mortar differ among Chinese, Japanese, Korean and Vietnamese folklore. In Chinese folklore, the rabbit is often portrayed as a companion of the Moon goddess Chang’e, constantly pounding the elixir of life for her and some show the making of cakes or rice cakes; but in Japanese and Korean versions, the rabbit is pounding the ingredients for mochi or some other type of rice cakes; in the Vietnamese version, the Moon rabbit often appears with Hằng Nga and Chú Cuội, and like the Chinese version, the Vietnamese Moon rabbit also pounding the elixir of immortality in the mortar. In some Chinese versions, the rabbit pounds medicine for the mortals and some include making of mooncakes. Moon folklore from certain Amerindian cultures of North America also has rabbit themes and characters.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/assets/images/Sun_Wukong_and_Jade_Rabbit.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/assets/images/Sun_Wukong_and_Jade_Rabbit.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AI and Animals</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/technology/2023/04/16/ai-and-animals.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI and Animals" /><published>2023-04-16T16:38:06+02:00</published><updated>2023-04-16T16:38:06+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/technology/2023/04/16/ai-and-animals</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/technology/2023/04/16/ai-and-animals.html"><![CDATA[<p>In the 1970s a young gorilla known as Koko drew worldwide attention with her ability to use human sign language. But skeptics maintain that Koko and other animals that “learned” to speak (including chimpanzees and dolphins) could not truly understand what they were “saying”—and that trying to make other species use human language, in which symbols represent things that may not be physically present, is futile.</p>

<p>“There’s one set of researchers that’s keen on finding out whether animals can engage in symbolic communication and another set that says, ‘That is anthropomorphizing. We need to understand nonhuman communication on its own terms,’” says Karen Bakker, a professor at the University of British Columbia and a fellow at the Harvard Radcliffe Institute for Advanced Study. Now scientists are using improved sensors and artificial-intelligence technology to observe and decode how a broad range of species, including plants, already share information with their own methods. This field of “digital bioacoustics” is the subject of Bakker’s 2022 book The Sounds of Life: How Digital Technology Is Bringing Us Closer to the Worlds of Animals and Plants (Princeton University Press).</p>

<p>Scientific American spoke with Bakker about how technology can help humans communicate with creatures such as bats and honeybees—and how these conversations are forcing us to rethink our relationship with other species.
Advertisement</p>

<p><strong>[An edited transcript of the interview follows.]</strong></p>

<p>Can you give us a brief history of humans attempting to communicate with animals?</p>

<p>There were numerous attempts in the mid-20th century to try to teach human language to nonhumans, primates such as Koko. And those efforts were somewhat controversial. As we look back, one view we have now (that may not have been so prevalent then) is that we were too anthropocentric in our approaches. The desire then was to assess nonhuman intelligence by teaching nonhumans to speak like we do—when in fact we should have been thinking about their abilities to engage in complex communication on their own terms, in their own embodied way, in their own worldview.</p>

<p>One of the terms used in the book is the notion of umwelt, which is this idea of the lived experience of organisms. If we are attentive to the umwelt of another organism, we wouldn’t expect a honeybee to speak human language, but we would become very interested in the fascinating language of honeybees, which is vibrational and positional. It’s sensitive to nuances such as the polarization of sunlight that we can’t even begin to convey with our bodies. That is where the science is today. The field of digital bioacoustics—which is accelerating exponentially and unveiling fascinating findings about communication across the tree of life—is now approaching these animals and asking not “Can they speak like humans?” but “Can they communicate complex information to one another? How are they doing so? What is significant to them?” I would say that’s a more biocentric approach, or at the very least it’s less anthropocentric.</p>

<p>Taking a bigger view, I think it’s also important to acknowledge that listening to nature, “deep listening,” has a long and venerable tradition. It’s an ancient art that is still practiced in an unmediated form. There are long-standing Indigenous traditions of deep listening that are deeply attuned to nonhuman sounds. So if we combine digital listening—which is opening up vast new worlds of nonhuman sound and decoding that sound with artificial intelligence—with deep listening, I believe that we are on the brink of two important discoveries. The first is language in nonhumans. And that’s a very controversial statement, which we can dig into. The second is: I believe we’re at the brink of interspecies communication.</p>]]></content><author><name>Fergie1234</name></author><category term="technology" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the 1970s a young gorilla known as Koko drew worldwide attention with her ability to use human sign language. But skeptics maintain that Koko and other animals that “learned” to speak (including chimpanzees and dolphins) could not truly understand what they were “saying”—and that trying to make other species use human language, in which symbols represent things that may not be physically present, is futile.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/assets/images/computer_cat.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/assets/images/computer_cat.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Crocodile tears are actually very similar to our own</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/science/2023/04/15/crocodile-tears.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crocodile tears are actually very similar to our own" /><published>2023-04-15T16:38:06+02:00</published><updated>2023-04-15T16:38:06+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/science/2023/04/15/crocodile-tears</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/science/2023/04/15/crocodile-tears.html"><![CDATA[<p>Most of us think of tears as a human phenomenon, part of the complex fabric of human emotion. But they’re not just for crying: All vertebrates, even reptiles and birds, have tears, which are critical for maintaining healthy eyesight.</p>

<p>Now, a new study, published this week in the journal Frontiers in Veterinary Science, reveals that non-human animals’ tears are not so different from our own. The chemical similarities are so great, in fact, that the composition of other species’ tears—and how they’re adapted to their environments—may provide insights into better treatments for human eye disease.</p>

<p>Previously, scientists had studied closely only the tears of a handful of mammals, including humans, dogs, horses, camels, and monkeys. In the new study, Brazilian veterinarians analyzed the tears of reptiles and birds for the first time, focusing on seven species: barn owls, blue-and-yellow macaws, roadside hawks, turquoise-fronted Amazon parrots, broad-snouted caimans, loggerhead sea turtles, and red-footed tortoises.</p>

<p>Tears, which are emitted from tear ducts (in humans and some other mammals) or other similar glands, form a film over the eye that’s composed of three ingredients: mucus, water, and oil. The mucus coats the eye’s surface and helps to bind the film to the eye, the water is a natural saline solution containing crucial proteins and minerals, and the oil prevents the eye from drying out.</p>

<p>Humans are the only known species to produce emotional tears; the expression “crocodile tears,” which refers to a person’s phony display of emotion, comes from the mysterious tendency of crocodiles to release tears as they eat.</p>

<p>But tears play key roles beyond weeping, notes Lionel Sebbag, a veterinary ophthalmologist at Iowa State University, in Ames, who was not involved in the new research. They help with vision by lubricating the eye and clearing it of debris. They also protect the eye against infection and provide nutrition to the cornea, the eye’s clear outer layer, which lacks blood vessels, he says.</p>

<p>“It’s a fascinating look at such a diverse range of species,” Sebbag says of the new study.</p>]]></content><author><name>AnimalPosting</name></author><category term="science" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most of us think of tears as a human phenomenon, part of the complex fabric of human emotion. But they’re not just for crying: All vertebrates, even reptiles and birds, have tears, which are critical for maintaining healthy eyesight.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/assets/images/crocodile_tears.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/rachelblueearth/assets/images/crocodile_tears.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>